<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lateral Movement on Mohammad Mahdi Anbaraki</title><link>https://binophism.github.io/tags/lateral-movement/</link><description>Recent content in Lateral Movement on Mohammad Mahdi Anbaraki</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 05:55:28 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://binophism.github.io/tags/lateral-movement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lateral Movement via WMI and Threat Hunting Techniques Part 2.1</title><link>https://binophism.github.io/posts/wmi-for-lateral-movement-part2.1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 05:55:28 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://binophism.github.io/posts/wmi-for-lateral-movement-part2.1/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="steps-for-lateral-movement-in-a-microsoft-network-using-wmi">Steps for Lateral Movement in a Microsoft Network Using WMI&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To perform lateral movement within a Microsoft network leveraging WMI, follow these steps. The stages will be explained with practical examples using various approaches. It’s important to note that this is not an exhaustive list of methods for lateral movement with WMI, and this section will be updated regularly.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="step-1-reconnaissance">Step 1: Reconnaissance&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://binophism.github.io/images/recon.png" alt="">
Reconnaissance consists of techniques that involve adversaries actively or passively gathering information that can be used to support targeting. Such information may include details of the victim organization, infrastructure, or staff/personnel. This information can be leveraged by the adversary to aid in other phases of the adversary lifecycle, such as using gathered information to plan and execute Initial Access, to scope and prioritize post-compromise objectives, or to drive and lead further Reconnaissance efforts. For example, techniques such as port scanning, OSINT (Open Source Intelligence), and others can be mentioned.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lateral Movement via WMI and Threat Hunting Techniques Part 1</title><link>https://binophism.github.io/posts/wmi-for-lateral-movement-part1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 05:55:28 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://binophism.github.io/posts/wmi-for-lateral-movement-part1/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="what-is-windows-management-instrumentation-wmi">What is Windows Management Instrumentation (WMI)?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The WMI tool in Windows provides a variety of software management utilities for managing and controlling Windows systems and devices. It allows for the inspection of hardware, software, and system status information. This tool communicates through various protocols, enabling applications to retrieve and manage the information they need from the system. It is worth mentioning that WMI is based on the COM and DCOM protocols, and when we interact with WMI remotely, the DCOM protocol is utilized.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>